episode where I cover four things, what's on my mind this week? Recommended reading
without over-reliance on AI or hiring a team.
close the laptop for the weekend,
I'm your host, Joe Casabona, and here's what's on my mind for August 28th, 2026.
financier. Stanley Druckenmiller is in hot water this week for using AI to write
his criticism of Scott Bessant
and he said when facing this criticism that he's not embarrassed because using AI
to write is akin to using a calculator. When I do math problems,
I've seen this more than once over the past couple of weeks and I've even referred
to large language models as word calculators. But maybe I should stop because when
you say writing with AI is like using a calculator for math shows a deep misunderstanding
of math calculators and words,
there are stark differences. For example,
you still need to know the calculation you are trying to solve.
And maybe you're thinking, okay, well I know I want to criticize Scott Scent. Maybe
I even know I want to criticize him for inflation or tariffs or whatever, right?
Write me an article that does that.
But here's the other side of that argument.
Each math problem
As my computer science teacher back in college, Dr. McCloskey often said The beauty
of math is that it is not ambiguous.
You have a math problem, an equation, and it will yield one answer and the same answer
over and over again.
If you ask a large language model to criticize Scott Besson,
Claude will not output the same article twice.
If you give it a prompt of, I need an article that criticizes Scott Bessant on inflation,
you will get different articles every time
say to solve five times five,
you will get 25 every single time. If you're using a more advanced a scientific calculator
and you say, solve for 10
equals X over two, you'll get 20 every single time.
But that's not even
my biggest gripe with this analogy.
my biggest gripe with this analogy
is that it is extremely troubling
when people use calculators for basic math.
I recently paid for takeout with cash at a restaurant.
The total was $47 and 46 cents, and I handed the cashier $48.
She had no intention of giving me my change. And I looked at her
And she said, do you want the change? It's just a few cents.
I said, it's like 50 cents.
And she brought me two quarters
and I'm confident that she brought me two quarters because she didn't actually know
that the true change was 54 cents. And I just said like
She did not know the amount of change I was supposed to get.
This is something I see constantly. I was at an airport one time and
the guy who was ordering in front of me,
his total came to $10 and 19 cents. He hands the cashier a 20 and then says, oh,
So the cashier says, how much change are you supposed to get back? And the patron
said, I don't know.
I was like, guys, it's 6 cents. 6 cents, 25 minus 19. It
is extremely troubling. That's bad.
Everybody should be able to do basic math
in their head,
but
not being able to articulate
your own thoughts
without
assistance from ai,
is so
much
worse,
especially
Stanley Druckenmiller,
but you don't need to be a billionaire
to be able to state
your thoughts.
Do you have something on your mind? Let me know.
What do you think about my screed? Just now?
You can head over to streamlined feedback.com, write in or leave a voice note.
If you leave a voice note, I might even play it on the show.
Alright, let's get to recommended reading this week. The recommended reading is the
Unraveling of Podcaster Ashley Flowers True Crime Empire. This is from journalist
Ashley Carmen for Bloomberg.
I enjoyed the first couple of seasons of Serial.
I used to listen to Criminal by Phoebe Judge
and Dr. Death plus some limited run shows. Those were interesting to me, but
like an adverse effect on the way
I was thinking about stuff.
And to my knowledge, I haven't listened to any of
audio Chuck's shows Audio. Chuck is the company that Ashley Flowers
owns
The most interesting bit of this story for me is not necessarily
about Crime junkies or audio Chuck. It actually came towards the beginning of the
story for me and I'm gonna read this verbatim from the article.
A growing number of top performers from Call her Daddy's Alex Cooper to Jimmy Donaldson,
AKA Mr. Beast are attempting to parlay their internet clout into broader, more diversified
companies.
But such transitions can be difficult
leadership duties while continuing to star on podcasts or YouTube channels with intensely
demanding schedules. Often it amounts to a frantic juggling act for even the most
industrious hustlers
end quote.
I see a lot of parallels between the personalities described here and solopreneurs.
The resources that you have at your disposal
appeal,
something like that. You try to grow beyond yourself. You cannot do it by yourself.
I knew when I made the decision to stay a company of one
that I wasn't going to build an empire or generate massive generational wealth.
But I did know that I could make more than enough money to support my family
and spend time with my kids.
I think the framing of this story is also interesting to me as a dad who has made
very different decisions from a lot of business owners.
Ashley Flowers admitted that she killed a popular show to spend more time with her
young daughter, but later in the article it quotes her as saying this
quote,
No one at this company works more hours than I do. Yes, I am the founder, but that
is not why.
It's because I care so much about this company and the work we do.
I regularly set my alarm at two or 3:00 AM and work over the weekend holidays and
when I'm sick,
that statement
feels diametrically opposed
Unless you're saying, I set my alarm at two or 3:00 AM so I can work from three to
seven before she wakes up. But I don't think that's the implication here.
'cause she's also saying she works weekends, holidays
I think two things can be true.
The story routinely states how things that she tried delegating out, she took back
over
And this is a parable for us as solo operators as well.
How many times have you said No one can do what I can do?
Increasingly automated systems can take a lot off of our plate.
And if our goal really is time freedom,
well, we should let those automated systems take things off of our plate.
I'm not saying you need to hire,
I don't want to hire any full-time employees. I have a VA
and a couple of other contractors to do things that I literally don't know, like
can't do. Well I
don't have any employees and I never intend on having employees,
but that doesn't mean you can't take things off of your plate.
You can and you should.
So I think that article's really interesting.
Alright, let's move over to something fun.
The something fun this week is
one of my favorite YouTube channels, epic Rap Battles of history
or ERB
has a new video out Tom Cruise versus Evil Knievel.
I love epic rap battles of history. I think they are clever, well researched and
catchy. My wife, when she was pregnant with our oldest, was worried that our daughter
would be born knowing some of these epic rap battles of history because I listened
to them so much.
But I also appreciate that the guys took a step back from doing videos every two
weeks to prevent burnout from them and their team. It's kind of like the opposite
of what you see
in the Crime Junkie story.
They were doing too much
in too little of amount of time and they took a step back. And even though they went
from publishing fortnightly
This one, Tom Cruise versus Evil Knievel is just as funny as and and Clever as their
Plus the guy they hired to play Tom Cruise is, is
incredible. At first I thought it was one of the guys. Nice Peter. Then I realized
it wasn't. Then I
thought, is that,
Uh, so the guy that they hired to play Tom Cruise is incredible. I think he's, I
think his handle on Instagram is at not Tom Cruise. So
check him out. Really good love, love their body of work.
this is a really good one
and uh,
I strongly recommend the channel in general.
Okay, moving on to something to help your systems.
I wanna talk about the stream deck today. And yes, I mean I talk about,
the stream deck a lot.
usually when I'm
talking about my systems, right? But over the past few weeks I showed off my mad
stream deck skills.
Sorry, I'm not 20 anymore,
on calls and recordings and folks were really impressed by it. The ability for me
between cameras.
And while I've written about my stream decks several times,
it's always worth resurfacing. So in, in the description, in the show notes for this,
uh, you'll find a link to how I've configured my stream deck.
But if you're looking for a place to start, I'll put this video in the cards on YouTube.
And I think that that is a
keyboard shortcuts are great, but having a button with a label or a an icon is much,
much easier in my opinion. And
it's how I run this whole show. So
if you're looking for a great piece of hardware,
maybe there's gonna be a Labor Day sale.
Uh, as this episode comes out,
it is a week from Labor Day here in the United States.
Uh, the stream deck is, is a great purchase in my opinion.
These episodes are about taking more time off, especially on the weekends. And the
best way to do that is by having good systems in place, good solo ops.
If you join my newsletter, you will get weekly emails on top of these emails that
go out for the Friday wrap up. You'll get weekly emails on how to build systems that
will save you 25 hours per month without over-reliance on AI
or hiring a team.
You'll go from doing everything yourself to doing your most important work.
So you can sign up over at streamlined fm slash join.